MELHEM EL DIRANI

Front-end developer

SUMMARY

Melhem is a self-taught front-end web developer. He has extensive knowledge of JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Node.js as well as significant experience with popular libraries and frameworks such as React.



Maximos st. Saida, Lebanon



melhemdirani@hotmail.com



https://melhemdirani.github.io/Melhem/



+961 71 523 153



https://www.linkedin.com/in/melhem-el-dirani-8A657BA5/?_l=en_US

EDUCATION

Master Degree in Civil Engineering Rafik Hariri University - 2018

Bachelor Degree in Civil Engineering University of Illinois, 2004

LANGUAGES

ARABIC - NATIVE ENGLISH - ADVANCED FRENCH - BEGINNER GERMAN - BEGINNER

SKILLS

LANGUAGES

- JavaScript
- HTML
- CSS

TOOLS

- Sublime Text 3
- Visual Studio Code
- GitHub
- WordPress

LIBRARIES/ API

- React
- Node.js
- Material-UI
- SASS

STORAGE

Firebase

FRAMEWORK

- Redux
- GraphQL
- Apollo
- Express
- Context API

METHODOLOGIES

- Agile Development
- REST API
- Unit Testing

EXPERIENCE

Intern Frontend Web Developer

Sicilia Mia, 2021 to Present

Math & English Teacher

Fratelli Organization, 2019 to 2021

Volunteer

Fighters for Peace Organization, 2017 to Present

Camping and Hiking Event organizer

Stone Age, 2017 to 2019

COURSES

The Complete Web Developer

Zero to Mastery - 2020

Responsive Web Design

Free Code Camp - 2021

Front-End Web Development with React

Coursera - 2021

Complete React Developer

Zero to Mastery - 2021